<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ding Luo</title>
    <link>https://dldingluo.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ding Luo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dldingluo.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Creating a New Theme</title>
      <link>https://dldingluo.com/posts_copy/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dldingluo.com/posts_copy/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://dldingluo.com/posts_copy/migrate-from-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dldingluo.com/posts_copy/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Move static content to static Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png  should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png  Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>101 Series - PySpark and Databricks</title>
      <link>https://dldingluo.com/posts/2021/03/101-series-pyspark-and-databricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dldingluo.com/posts/2021/03/101-series-pyspark-and-databricks/</guid>
      <description>Hugo uses the excellent Go html/template library for its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of similarities in Go templates.
This document is a brief primer on using Go templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing GPS data for kepler.gl trip visualization</title>
      <link>https://dldingluo.com/posts/2021/03/preparing-gps-data-for-kepler.gl-trip-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dldingluo.com/posts/2021/03/preparing-gps-data-for-kepler.gl-trip-visualization/</guid>
      <description>Over the past years I have been using kepler.gl more and more often for geospatial visualiztion. The reason is just simple: powerful, easy, fast. It serves as a perfect visualization tool for EDA tasks. Very often when I show the visualization to my stakeholders, especially those who are from the traditional business side, they are immediately impressed!
In this post, I want to simply share some python scripts for preparing GPS trajectory data for kepler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>101 Series - Unit Testing</title>
      <link>https://dldingluo.com/posts/2021/02/101-series-unit-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dldingluo.com/posts/2021/02/101-series-unit-testing/</guid>
      <description>On my recent project, I have been learning a bunch of new things, which from my very own perspective are crucial to someone who wants to become a full-fledged data scientist (i.e., research &amp;amp; development). I am really excited about learning and practicing these new tools and skills on the job, and therefore decide to create my personal 101 series on them. The plan is to continously update and improve the content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>posts[0]</title>
      <link>https://dldingluo.com/posts/2021/02/posts0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dldingluo.com/posts/2021/02/posts0/</guid>
      <description>Recently I have found the motto below very motivating, which was quoted by one of our team members when trying to resolve a comment on his pull request.
So let&amp;rsquo;s kick off this post section and try to build stuff continously and incrementally.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://dldingluo.com/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dldingluo.com/research/</guid>
      <description>Entitled &amp;quot;Data-driven Analysis and Modeling of Public Transport Passenger Flows and Service Networks&amp;quot;, my PhD dissertation is about researching methods and models for developing insights into complex dynamics of public transport systems. These insights, which are unlocked through advanced data analytics, can be used to improve public transport planning and operations for building a better passenger mobility system for our society.
  Scientific Publications The research I conducted during my PhD has been published in the following well regarded academic journals in the domain of transport science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://dldingluo.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dldingluo.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello there! Welcome to my personal website. I am a (researcher-turned) data scientist based in the Netherlands. Currently I work for Shell primarily in the space of E-Mobility data analytics. I joined Shell as an AI resident straight after after completing my PhD program at TU Delft. Check out the research page for more details about what I did to earn the title of Dr.
In addition to my full-time role, I am also a guest researcher hosted by TU Delft&amp;rsquo;s AI for Mobility (AIM) Lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title>
      <link>https://dldingluo.com/posts_copy/goisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dldingluo.com/posts_copy/goisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Hugo uses the excellent Go html/template library for its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of similarities in Go templates.
This document is a brief primer on using Go templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://dldingluo.com/posts_copy/hugoisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dldingluo.com/posts_copy/hugoisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Step 1. Install Hugo $(document).ready(function() { console.log(&amp;#39;Ready!&amp;#39;); }); Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.
More complete instructions are available at Install Hugo
Step 2. Build the Docs Hugo has its own example site which happens to also be the documentation site you are reading right now.
Follow the following steps:
 Clone the Hugo repository Go into the repo Run hugo in server mode and build the docs Open your browser to http://localhost:1313  Corresponding pseudo commands:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
